# CAITLIN BOPP

Front-end web developer leveraging a marketing background to build intuitive user experiences on the web. Currently enrolled in a full stack development Bootcamp through Johns Hopkins University, developing skills in JavaScript, CSS, Express, and responsive web design. I am a mobile-first, design forward, problem solver with a passion to take a greater role in the delivery of front-end and backend projects. During my training I applied aspects of UX and agile development to build a portfolio, and the projects within. I have 8 years of experience in marketing and merchandising front-end sites through Slate, SiteCore CMS, Heiler, and SAP. I'm excited to develop my career as a developer and leverage my skills as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, ES6+, CSS3, HTML5

**Applications**: GitHub

Tools: jQuery, Node, Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS, Sequelize, Normalize, Bootstrap,

Express-Handlebars, MySql, Underscore

# **Projects**

### Boolean Bookworm | Github Repository Link | Link to Deployed Project

- Summary: An online bookclub community where users can discuss current book(s) being read, access their own personal profile, and add books to their own personal reading list.
- Role: Co-author
- Tools: Node.js, Sequelize ORM, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Normalize, Bootstrap, JSON API, Bcrypt, Connect-Session-Sequelize, Dotenv, Express-Handlebars, Express-Session MySql, MySql2, Sequelize, Underscore

### Yoda Advice | Github Repository Link | Link to Deployed Project

- **Summary:** Users will be able to receive sage advice from the venerable Jedi Master, Yoda. In addition to translating random pieces of advice into Yoda's famous way of speaking, users can also create their own pieces of advice for Yoda to translate.
- Role: Co-author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MaterializeCSS, Fun Translations API, Advice Slip ISON API

# Workday Scheduler | Github Repository Link | Link to Deployed Project

- **Summary:** An interactive calendar app for scheduling your workday.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, GoogleFonts

### Code Quiz | Github Repository Link | Link to Deployed Project

- **Summary:** A timed quiz consisting of multiple-choice coding questions.
- **Role:** Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

# CONTACT

- boppcaitlin@gmail.com
- 410-868-2677
- 2206 Lake Ave. Baltimore, MD 21213
- in linkedin.com/in/caitlinbopp

# SKILLS

### **Adobe Creative Suite**

Adobe Acrobat, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, AfterEffects, Bridge

#### **Microsoft Office**

Microsoft Word, Excel, Powerpoint

### Social Media

Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, LinkedIn, Pinterest, Canva, Hootsuite

#### **Content Management**

Sitecore, Informatica PIM

# Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Slate, First Spirit

### **Analytics**

Google Analytics, SimplyMeasured, Hootsuite, Tableau

# **EDUCATION**

# Bachelors of Science, Marketing & Advertising

Rider University, NJ 2009 - 2013

# **AWARDS**

# Full Division I Women's Basketball Scholarship

Rider University, NJ 2009 - 2013

# CAITLIN BOPP

# **EXPERIENCE**

## ASSISTANT DIRECTOR, ENROLLMENT MARKETING & COMMUNICATIONS

Loyola University Maryland, Baltimore, MD / October 2018 - Present

- Maintains all undergraduate admission website content
- Manages multiple third-party vendor relationships
- Manages all undergraduate admission event communication
- Oversees all transfer undergraduate admission email communication through customer relationship management system (CRM)
- Assists with all undergraduate admission email marketing communications (setup, scheduling, copy edits)
- Maintains monthly social media content calendar
- Creates original video content for social media platforms
- Oversees all undergraduate admission social media platforms

#### DIRECTOR OF ADMISSIONS

Institute of Notre Dame, Baltimore, MD / July 2017 - October 2018

- Oversaw the recruitment, evaluation, and admissions process for prospective students
- Supervised Admissions office staff, and regularly reported to Head of School
- Built and reported on monthly metrics to school board
- Coordinated and facilitated on and off-campus recruiting events
- Coordinated campus tours for prospective students and families
- Reviewed all applications and documentation for each applicant
- Performed both phone and in-person admissions interviews
- Oversaw financial aid and scholarship programs

### MARKETING SPECIALIST

BLANCO America, Inc., Lumberton, NJ / May 2013 - May 2017

- Managed day-to-day marketing budget tracking process
- Managed new product marketing communications
- Supported new collateral development for all key literature pieces (including proofing and managing project deadlines
- Assisted in development of training platforms for sales reps and customers
- Managed third party fulfillment center
- Supervised onsite press checks for all printed literature
- Managed video production process
- Oversaw all content management for U.S. website
- Built and reported monthly website metrics and analytics to marketing team
- Supported photoshoot management, and assisted with photoshoot set designs
- Coordinated all product shipments for photoshoots, trade shows, and all marketing or sales events
- Managed customer product data requests
- Oversaw all social media platforms
- Organized national sales meeting